<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Mark Lewis</author>
  <term>Content Standard</term>
  <what>A design or definition (expressed in a modeling language)
    considered by an authority as an approved model. Standards include
    structural and semantic models, processes, and presentation
    semantics models.</what>
  <why>Provides a normative language that facilitates exchange between
    systems, process automation, and process integration. Enables
    search, retrieval, sorting, content management, workflow, and
    publishing.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>Mark Lewis is the author of <link
        href="http://ditametrics101.com/">DITA Metrics 101</link> and is
      a contributing author of <link href="http://www.dita101.com/">DITA
        101: Fundamentals of the Darwin Information Architecture for
        Authors and Managers</link>, second edition. He manages the
        <link
        href="http://www.linkedin.com/groups/DITA-Metrics-2916249/about"
        >DITA Metrics</link> LinkedIn group and is a presenter at
      content industry events. Mark is a Content Engineer and DITA
      Educator for <link href="http://www.quark.com/">Quark</link>.</p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/mlewis-7234-pp-mlewis.png"/>
  <email>mlewis@ditametrics.com</email>
  <website>http://www.ditametrics.com</website>
  <twitter>@LewisDITAMetric</twitter>
  <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/marklewisflorida/</linkedin>
  <facebook>https://www.facebook.com/#!/mark.lewis.10420</facebook>
  <description>
    <p>The goal of a content standard is to facilitate the
      implementation of a content strategy and the creation and
      publication of content. Through the course of the content
      lifecycle, multiple humans and systems may need to access and
      affect content. A content standard facilitates this by providing a
      common technical language so that content elements, metadata, and
      processes are consistent and predictable. When content is
      standards-based, interoperability between content, humans, and
      systems is possible.</p>
    <p>Processes help implement a content strategy and the phases of the
      content lifecycle. These processes may be manual or automated.
      Standards-based content is predictable to both humans and
      machines, which supports functionality such as searching,
      retrieval, sorting, filtering, indexing, tracking, and reporting.
      These functions are then available to processes and to systems
      such as content management, workflow, and publishing.</p>
    <p>Standards also help facilitate a content strategy through
      validation, transformation, and adaptation. Standards-based
      content can be tested against the defined model to ensure that the
      content conforms to the rules established to support the content
      strategy. Content in one standard can be more readily transformed
      or converted to another standard. This is necessary for publishing
      and also allows content to be future proofed and adaptive. Content
      that is format free, device independent, and scalable is future
      proof and can adapt to new strategies, global strategies,
      standards, and display devices that haven’t been designed yet. </p>
    <p>When a standard is adopted, it allows humans and machines to play
      well with each other in the content sandbox.</p>
  </description>
  <resources>
    <list>
      <item>
        <p><link href="http://w3.org/">W3C (World Wide Web
            Consortium)</link>, responsible for the HTML, CSS, SVG, and
          XML standards.</p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p><link href="http://oasis-open.org/">OASIS (Organization for
            the Advancement of Structured Information Standards)</link>,
          responsible for the DITA and DocBook standards</p>
      </item>
    </list>
  </resources>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/content-standard</audio>
</topic>