<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Scott Abel</author>
  <term>Content </term>
  <what>Any text, image, video, decoration, or user-consumable elements that contribute to
    comprehension.</what>
  <why>Content is the single most-used way of understanding an organization's products or services,
    stories, and brand.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>Known as <link href="http://www.thecontentwrangler.com/">The
        Content Wrangler</link>, Scott Abel is an internationally
      recognized global content strategist, lecturer at the University
      of California, Berkeley, <link
        href="http://www.ischool.berkeley.edu/people/faculty">School of
        Information</link>, <link
        href="http://www.econtentmag.com/Authors/4218-Scott-Abel.htm"
        >EContent Magazine</link> columnist, and a vibrant speaker
      frequently employed at content industry events. He co-produces
      several content industry events including <link
        href="http://www.contentstrategyworkshops.com/">Content Strategy
        Workshops</link> and the <link
        href="http://www.intelligentcontentconference.com/">Intelligent
        Content Conference</link>. Scott’s message is clear: Content is
      a business asset worth managing efficiently and effectively. He
      works to help content-heavy organizations adopt the tools,
      technologies, and techniques needed to connect content to
      customers.</p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/scottProfilePhoto.png"/>
  <email>scott@thecontentwrangler.com</email>
  <website>www.thecontentwrangler.com</website>
  <twitter>@scottable</twitter>
  <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/scottabel</linkedin>
  <facebook>https://www.facebook.com/scottpatrickabel</facebook>
  <description>
    <p>Content can be described in several ways, some technical, others
      conceptual:</p>
    <list>
      <item>
        <p><strong>Contextualized data:</strong> Data is a context-free
          value; content has enough context to aid with consumer
          comprehension. For example, the number “12” is merely data.
          Adding context to the data, such as 12th month or 12 years
          old, imbues the data with meaning and creates content.</p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p><strong>The stuff inside a container:</strong> In a world
          where content is virtually always touched by technology, this
          means content is between a set of standardized markup tags,
          allowing technology to automate the processing of content.</p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p><strong>An extension of the user experience:</strong> Content
          is the treasure at the end of the treasure hunt. Without good
          content, the best user experience falls flat.</p>
      </item>
    </list>
    <p>Most importantly, <emphasis>content is a business
        asset</emphasis> that we use to communicate with our customers,
      prospects, and investors. Content is how we communicate our brand,
      how we acquire and retain customers, how we drive our reputations,
      and how we build a social enterprise. It is the lifeblood of any
      organization. </p>
    <p>To develop effective content strategies, it is important to
      understand both the editorial and technical sides of content.</p>
    <list>
      <item>
        <p>Editorially, content should be relevant, accurate,
          informative, timely, and engaging and should conform to
          editorial standards.</p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Technically, content should be standards-based, use
          well-formed schemas, be semantically rich for filtering and
          findability, and be structured to support automated
          delivery.</p>
      </item>
    </list>
    <p>This allows content to be converged, integrated, and
      syndicated—all important aspects of leveraging content to its
      fullest potential.</p>
  </description>
  <resources>
    <p><link href="http://xmlpress.net/publications/the-content-pool/"
        >The Content Pool: Leveraging Your Company’s Largest Hidden
        Asset</link> by Alan J. Porter (XML Press)</p>
    <p><link href="http://www.contentiscurrency.com/">Content is
        Currency: Developing Powerful Content for Web and Mobile</link>
      by Jon Wuebben (Nicholas Brealey Publishing)</p>
  </resources>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/content</audio>
</topic>
