<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Robert Rose</author>
  <term>Content Lifecycle</term>
  <what>The process that defines the series of changes in the life of
    any piece of content, including reproduction, from creation
    onward.</what>
  <why>Content creates meaning; the content lifecycle creates a
    repeatable process that defines how meaningful communication will be
    managed.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>Robert Rose helps marketers become stellar storytellers. He is
      the Chief Strategist for the <link
        href="http://www.contentmarketinginstitute.com/">Content
        Marketing Institute</link>, and Senior Contributing Analyst for
        <link href="http://www.digitalclaritygroup.com/">Digital Clarity
        Group</link>. Robert is the author of the industry-leading book
        <link href="http://managingcontentmarketing.wordpress.com/"
        >Managing Content Marketing</link>, which spent two weeks as a
      top 10 marketing book on <link href="http://amazon.com/"
        >Amazon.com</link>.</p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/rroseProfilePhoto.png"/>
  <email>robert@bigbluemoose.net</email>
  <website>http://www.robert-rose.com</website>
  <twitter>@Robert_Rose</twitter>
  <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/robrose</linkedin>
  <facebook>http://www.Facebook.com/TheRobertRose</facebook>
  <description>
    <p>The content lifecycle includes five general stages:</p>
    <list>
      <item>
        <p>Strategic analysis </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Content collection </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Content management </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Publication and post-publication maintenance </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Preservation or re-purposing of content and a loop back to
          analysis for the next cycle</p>
      </item>
    </list>
    <p>Content is a business asset that should be managed as carefully
      as any product or differentiating intellectual property. An
      organization’s ability to have efficient and effective management
      of its content through the entire lifecycle can mean the
      difference between success and failure.</p>
    <p>The stages within the content lifecycle can have sub-stages that
      depend on the origins, purposes, and governance models of the
      content. These may include sub-stages that support specific
      channels such as web content, print, or email or specific formats
      of content such as spoken word, video, text, or images.</p>
    <p>It is less important what the stages are called and more
      important that the practitioner have a unified process for
      managing the entirety of the lifecycle. As Ann Rockley wrote in
      her seminal work, <link
        href="http://www.managingenterprisecontent.com/">Managing
        Enterprise Content: A Unified Content Strategy</link>, to
      counter content silos, the practitioner should create “a
      repeatable method of identifying all content requirements up
      front, creating consistently structured content for reuse,
      managing that content in a definitive source, and assembling
      content on demand to meet your customer’s needs.”</p>
  </description>
  <resources>
    <p><link
        href="http://www.gollner.ca/2013/09/the-content-lifecycle.html"
        >The Content Lifecycle</link> by Joe Gollner</p>
  </resources>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/content-lifecycle</audio>
</topic>