<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Colleen Jones</author>
  <term>Content Brief</term>
  <what>A summary or statement of your plan for a content project. For
    large projects, a content brief summarizes your plan for each
    project phase.</what>
  <why>By clearly answering key questions about your content, the
    content brief reduces the risk of content issues causing delays. The
    brief also makes communicating about content during the project
    faster, easier, and more effective.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>As principal of Content Science and author of the top-selling
      industry book, <link
        href="http://content-science.com/clout-the-book">Clout</link>,
      Colleen Jones has advised organizations ranging from Dell to The
      Coca-Cola Company to Wiley. With an M.A. and over 15 years of
      experience, Colleen regularly speaks at industry conferences
      around the world and gives guest lectures for academic
      institutions.</p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/cjonesProfilePhoto.png"/>
  <email>colleen@content-science.com</email>
  <website>http://content-science.com</website>
  <twitter>@leenjones</twitter>
  <linkedin>www.linkedin.com/in/leenjones</linkedin>
  <facebook/>
  <description>
    <p>Content strategists need this term and, more importantly, this
      tool so they can communicate effectively about content throughout
      a project or project phase. The content brief aligns everyone
      involved in content around the vision or goal and the approach to
      achieving it. As a project progresses, when questions arise, new
      people get involved, or your team must make decisions, the content
      brief will help everyone involved stay true to the content vision
      and approach.</p>
    <p>Typically, the content brief answers the six W and H questions
      including (but not limited to):</p>
    
    <list>
      <item>
        <p>What are we trying to achieve with content? </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Why are we trying to achieve it—to meet what business or
          organizational purpose? </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Who is our audience? </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Who will be involved in planning, creating, and maintaining
          content? </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>When will our audience need or expect content? </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>When will we plan, create, and maintain content? </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>Where do our audiences need or expect content and in what
          formats? </p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p>How will we structure our content for our content management
          system?</p>
      </item>
    </list>
    <p>Do not assume that a creative brief, a design brief, or a
      technology brief will cover content! Usually, those briefs leave
      content out or address only certain aspects of content. Content is
      critical to most projects, and content is often complex and
      involves many stakeholders. Therefore, content deserves its own
      brief. </p>
  
  </description>
  <resources>
    <p><link href="http://content-science.com/clout-the-book/">Clout:
        The Art + Science of Influential Web Content</link></p>
  </resources>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/12-content-brief-content-strategy-term-of-the-week</audio>
</topic>