<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Laurence Dansokho</author>
  <term>Content Quality Assurance</term>
  <what>A systematic process to ensure that content meets specified
    requirements before publishing.</what>
  <why>To measure the quality of the content creation process and ensure
    that content deliverables are completed with an acceptable level of
    quality.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>Laurence Dansokho is Tools and Process Manager at <link
        href="http://www.ebay.com/">eBay</link>, responsible for global
      content process optimization and quality control. She graduated in
      journalism at the University of Leipzig, has quality management
      experience, including a Six Sigma Yellow Belt and certification in
        <link
        href="http://www.iso.org/iso/catalogue_detail?csnumber=46486"
        >ISO 9001:2008 Quality Management</link>, and is also a
      certified Usability Practitioner. </p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/ldansokhoProfilePhoto.png"/>
  <email>fazut@web.de</email>
  <website/>
  <twitter>@LaurenceFD</twitter>
  <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/pub/laurence-dansokho/8/344/a22</linkedin>
  <facebook/>
  <description>
    <p>Content quality assurance is a key component of content quality
      management. Quality assurance focuses on the processes you use to
      develop content, ensuring that your content creation processes
      produce quality deliverables. Content quality assurance
      comprises:</p>
    <list>
      <item>
        <p><strong>Content creation processes:</strong> For example,
          authoring and page building processes.</p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p><strong>Quality standards and stakeholder
            expectations:</strong> For example, tone and voice
          compliance, style guide compliance, link standards, and
          content accuracy.</p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p><strong>Quality assurance activities that monitor content
            creation:</strong> For example, quality audits, reviews
          against authoring guidelines, peer reviews, subject matter
          expert reviews, page load time tests, link tests, and
          usability tests.</p>
      </item>
      <item>
        <p><strong>Quality assurance scheduling:</strong> For example,
          schedules for how often and when quality assurance activities
          will be performed.</p>
      </item>
    </list>
    <p>Quality targets depend on the project, and you need to identify
      targets for each content deliverable. You can create a content
      quality scorecard, which could indicate fail/pass or a way to rank
      the issues. This will help you prioritize and identify improvement
      opportunities.</p>
  </description>
  <resources/>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/content-quality-assurance</audio>
</topic>