<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Rahel Anne Bailie</author>
  <term>Content Strategy</term>
  <what>The analysis and planning to develop a repeatable system that
    governs the management of content throughout the entire content
    lifecycle.</what>
  <why>Provides context, so that the organization’s vision can be
    implemented in an integrated way, to meet business goals and project
    objectives.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>Rahel Anne Bailie is an integrator of content strategy,
      requirements analysis, information architecture, and content
      management to increase ROI of product lifecycle content. She is
      also a supporter of content structure and standards. She is
      founder of <link href="http://intentionaldesign.ca/">Intentional
        Design</link>, Fellow of <link href="http://stc.org/"
      >STC</link>, co-author of Content Strategy: <link
        href="http://www.thecontentstrategybook.com/">Connecting the
        dots between business, brand, and benefits, and
        co-producer</link> of <link
        href="http://www.contentstrategyworkshops.com/">Content Strategy
        Workshops</link>.</p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/rabailieProfilePhoto.png"/>
  <email>rabailie@intentionaldesign.ca</email>
  <website>http://www.intentionaldesign.ca</website>
  <twitter>@rahelab</twitter>
  <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/rahelannebailie</linkedin>
  <facebook>https://www.facebook.com/pages/Intentional-Design/208164155867779</facebook>
  <facebook>https://www.facebook.com/thecontentstrategybook</facebook>
  <facebook>https://www.facebook.com/ContentStrategyWorkshops</facebook>
  <description>
    <p>Strategy is defined as “alternatives chosen to make happen a
      desired future, such as achievement of a goal or solution to a
      problem.” A content strategy, then, is the analysis phase of a
      business problem that determines how content can be improved,
      either on the editorial or technical sides, to contribute to
      corporate success.</p>
    <p>To understand what content strategy <emphasis>is</emphasis>, we
      need to eliminate what it <emphasis>is not</emphasis>. A content
      strategy does not include activities that lead to project
      deliverables, such as an audit—those are tactical-level aspects of
      implementation. The strategy is the phase that comes
        <emphasis>before</emphasis> any of these activities, and it
      determines what activities are needed to achieve success.</p>
    <p>Content strategy is the practice of helping organizations improve
      their content performance, primarily through the analysis of
      existing content problems and development of plans for
      improvement. A content strategy will assess an organization’s
      current state, understand the ideal future state, recognize where
      the gaps are, and develop an implementation roadmap.  </p>
    <p>The roadmap defines a content lifecycle specific to an
      organization’s needs, so that the content can meet business goals.
      Even when a project or contract addresses only a portion of the
      overall need, the strategy should be designed to allow future
      projects to become part of a unified strategy.</p>
  </description>
  <resources>
    <p><link href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Management_consulting"
        >http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Management_consulting</link></p>
    <p><link href="http://www.managingenterprisecontent.com/">Managing
        Enterprise Content: A Unified Content Strategy</link> by Ann
      Rockley and Charles Cooper (New Riders)</p>
  </resources>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/content-strategy</audio>
</topic>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>