<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Cheryl Landes</author>
  <term>Findability</term>
  <what>The quality of being able to be discovered and retrieved through
    searching or browsing.</what>
  <why>Content must be found to be consumed. Therefore, findability is
    critical in a world with a growing demand for fast, contextual
    retrieval of information.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>Cheryl Landes founded <link
        href="http://www.tabbycatco.com/about.html">Tabby Cat
        Communications</link> in Seattle in 1995. She has 22 years of
      experience as a technical communicator in computer software,
      HVAC/energy savings, marine transportation, manufacturing, and
      retail. She specializes as a findability strategist, helping
      businesses organize content to flow logically and make content
      easier to retrieve.</p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/clandes-94833-pp-clandes.png"/>
  <email>clandes407@aol.com</email>
  <website>www.tabbycatco.com</website>
  <twitter>@landesc</twitter>
  <linkedin>www.linkedin.com/in/clandes</linkedin>
  <facebook>https://www.facebook.com/cheryl.landes.58</facebook>
  <description>
    <p>“The reason people hire content strategists is that people can’t
      find anything,” says content strategy expert, Rahel Anne
      Bailie.</p>
    <p>Your organization can have the best content: simple,
      understandable technical documentation; elegant, cleverly crafted
      marketing prose; or viral-worthy videos. But if search engines
      cannot understand your content or consumers can’t find it, then no
      one will ever get to read that information or watch that video.
      Content is only as good as the consumer’s ability to find it
      quickly and easily. If they can’t find your content, they’ll look
      elsewhere.</p>
    <p>Readers find information with a combination of two intentional
      methods: navigation and search. However, they also encounter
      information. </p>
    <p><emphasis>Navigation</emphasis> means using the available options
      and contextual clues to locate content. Buttons, tabs, tables of
      contents, menus, links, and indexes are common navigation options
      online. In print, readers navigate with the help of tables of
      content, indices, and page numbers.</p>
    <p><emphasis>Search</emphasis> is the act of looking for specific
      content by entering a query in a search engine or application.
      Users form queries with keywords or search terms, and the search
      engine displays the query results based on its index and
      understanding of the request.</p>
    <p>Increasing the findability of content means ensuring that content
      has appropriate metadata and structure so that search engines and
      consumers can locate and retrieve relevant content as needed—as
      well as making it more likely consumers will encounter the
      information they need. Well-designed navigation and content
      designed for search help serve up the content consumers want, when
      they want it.</p>
  </description>
  <resources>
    <p><link
        href="http://www.amazon.com/Ambient-Findability-Peter-Morville/dp/0596007655/findability-20/"
        >Ambient Findability</link>, by Peter Morville. O'Reilly Media.
      2009.</p>
    <p><link
        href="http://www.amazon.com/Information-Architecture-World-Wide-Web/dp/0596527349"
        >Information Architecture for the World Wide Web</link>, by
      Peter Morville and Louis Rosenfeld. O'Reilly Media. 3rd Edition,
      2006.</p>
  </resources>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/findability</audio>
</topic>