<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/ns/languageBook">
  <author>Kate Kenyon</author>
  <term>Requirements Matrix</term>
  <what>A tool for assessing content priorities against defined business
    needs, where prioritized business goals and requirements are mapped
    against an organization’s content.</what>
  <why>Aligns content to agreed business goals, meaning content
    decisions are prioritized without politics. Content is transformed
    into a business asset: measurable, auditable, and with a defined
    return on investment.</why>
  <bio>
    <p>Kate Kenyon specializes in enterprise-level content strategy,
      site migration, content management system specification, business
      process design, and helping organizations set key performance
      indicators: all the nasty, sticky bits of content strategy that
      she finds weirdly interesting. She is active in the London content
      strategy community and speaks at content strategy events across
      the United Kingdom.</p>
  </bio>
  <picture href="../images/kkenyonProfilePhoto.png"/>
  <email>Kate@whipsmartcontent.com</email>
  <website>http://www.whipsmartcontent.com</website>
  <twitter>@kate_kenyon</twitter>
  <linkedin>http://www.linkedin.com/in/katekenyon</linkedin>
  <facebook/>
  <description>
    <p>A content matrix sets a benchmark for current business
      priorities, and aligns content to the delivery of those
      priorities. Not all projects need a requirements matrix. It is
      usually a large, multiple-tab spreadsheet that requires ownership
      and ongoing updates as business priorities change. However, when
      struggling with multiple or conflicted stakeholders who cannot
      agree what content to produce and when, a matrix is a useful tool.
      A requirements matrix can also be used for new sites, for major
      content migrations, or even for orchestrating multi-platform
      campaigns where content is being produced by more than one
      team.</p>
    <p>A requirements matrix should include a list of business
      requirements, a description of the requirements, and a scoring
      system (for example, 1-2-3 or Must Have/Should Have/Nice to Have)
      that prioritizes content according to the stated business goals.
      For example, “Will this content help company X capture a greater
      share of Market Y?”</p>
    <p>Prioritizing this way means that metrics become important. Some
      matrices also include anticipated outcomes and metrics for success
      so that content can be audited and a return on investment
      established.</p>
    <p>An organization’s ability to deliver on specific requirements can
      also be included. Some matrices factor in technical complexity,
      resourcing, frequency of updates, and other factors that could
      affect the success of the content throughout its lifecycle.</p>
    <p>A requirements matrix keeps stakeholders and businesses focused
      on why they produce content, rather than simply what should be
      created.</p>
  </description>
  <resources/>
  <audio>https://soundcloud.com/theaudiowrangler/13-content-strategy-term-of-the-week-requirements-matrix</audio>
</topic>